all right welcome to today's solution
raising we are discussing loneliness
because it is what i am struggling with
in cobit 19. thank you to carrie for
talking me through some stuff yesterday
and being a adventurer
no problem and so if anyone would like
to share currently what loneliness looks
like in the world in your life
and then of course move on to the second
part of
what we would like it to look like in a
ideal world and then what could actually
we could do
to combat loneliness with ten thousand
people and a hundred thousand dollars
if and when we have that would anybody
like
the funny thing it's a funny thing
lonely i mean i think to an outside
observer if they looked at my life they
would think
i must be lonely right because i spend a
lot of time
on my own and yet i rarely if ever
experience loneliness in a sort of you
know in any kind of
bothersome sort of way um and
so yeah it's it's it's interesting i
think it's it's a very different thing
for different people i think some people
are lonely if they're on their own for
an hour
and other people can you know go on a
75-day retreat or whatever on their own
what's his name daniel thorson did a
75-day
you know silence on his own retreat you
know and and i doubt he felt lonely for
any of that so
yeah it's uh that that's all i really
was gonna that's what i really want to
say is that it's a very different thing
for different people
well also yeah that that is maybe
part of what we're discussing here is
not what society thinks is lonely right
like i wouldn't think of you as lonely
unless you told me you were lonely
it's like an inner inner feeling i feel
very grateful right now as i have for
almost a year
for game b and i am not lonely within
game b i found people to talk to about
what i want to talk to
but with covid19 i've realized how much
my in-person community is lacking both
the one i thought was here
like i suck i haven't contacted them and
i haven't really stayed in contact
but also they haven't checked on me and
they haven't and there's a certain sense
of
like i've never been more lonely than
when i'm at a party like when i'm
at with people who i think should be
seen and be
like with and i feel like i'm not seen
and i'm not accepted and i'm not
and how much of that is on me and it's
not the truth and then how much
is on the other and is there any any
other solution i think that
for most people this world is very
lonely even if you're
introverted and good at meeting people
so you have less of a social need and
you're good at meeting it
it can still be a lonely place when you
then put into it when you're
extroverted you need even more
connection and maybe you suck at getting
connection
maybe you're autistic maybe you have
some interpersonal stuff
um which i do like it's there's a
certain
everything that is out there for
connection also is designed to the
people who already
are extroverted and already have the
skills it's like sell yourself
to everyone else so you can meet friends
instead of making it more easy for
people and helping like everyone wants
to be seen yet we're all trying to be
versions of ourselves so we can be liked
by everyone else
when there's nothing lonelier than that
because even if they like you
they don't like you and and that's the
world i'm living in like the more i
become myself the more
i love me and i'm connected and i'm
finding the right people the people who
do like me and accept me
and at the same time the more truly
isolated i am because the less i fit in
and people don't want me around as much
because all i want to talk about is game
b
or the equivalent but i will let the
next person sure
i can go um i'm reminded of a
part of a richard rohr book where he
emphasizes
the extreme need to really be yourself
that any years of his life where he was
putting up any kind of facade
to to be loved more just
it never works out in the long run um
so that's seems like that's part of it
uh
um yeah i i like what you said about
how there are it does mean different
things to different people
you know we've got introverts and we've
got extroverts
i like to think of uh part of this as
the need
to be known the need to
know other people but also be known
i think that for me i have kind of
different types of friends
um and like ideally they cross all these
boundaries or they they you know i the
best friends
are in these different groups but you
know i've got like my athletic
friends that i like to go biking with or
do sports with
and then i've got some of my more maybe
more intellectual friends that we can
just sit around and talk about subjects
for hours
they don't always overlap uh some of my
intellectual friends you know the worst
thing they could think of is like
going running like no way um
and some of my um like athletic friends
don't necessarily want to just sit
around
and chat for hours um
and let's see uh i had one other thing
um
maybe it'll come back to me um
yeah those are some of my thoughts
though that it has something to do with
uh with being known um
is oh i was thinking about so
uh there are bad cures for loneliness
and for me
i was caught up in addiction and
drinking
a lot and so that was a bad
resolve for loneliness that was numbing
out
um and then you know i actually had to
distance myself from a lot of friends
that are in lifestyles that i don't want
to participate in anymore
and so um kind of halfway through life
having to build new connections so i
have all these memories with these folks
but we have distance now and so
part of being less lonely to me is
building new memories i can't go back
and i can't do school and i can't do
these
different memories that i'll never get
back with
folks that i did a lot of substances
with
but i need to build new memories with
folks
that are would make better friends
um and so it's like hey let's
build memories by doing extraordinary
things and
that is bonding
uh okay um loneliness right
well i think i'm going to be one of
these people who ends up
dead behind the dawns not phone for six
months till the neighbors know the smell
because because people will just think
i'm up to stuff you know i mean
so um i quite like being on my own but
there's
times um because i have a tendency to be
all in
a kind of friendship and that so
when that's not forthcoming and it's not
like a two-way street then i do feel
kind of
lonely and that even though and i
realize i've got more
acquaintances and really good friends um
i came across
aristotle's three types of friendship
the other day
once uh the first two were utility and
pleasure so like as you said daniel the
utility of friends who
you get benefit from or useful to you so
while you were at your drinking stage
that would have been the utility and
they don't last very long obviously
people move on
and that you know and the pleasure ones
of the ones you like hanging out with
but you know
you don't help you grow in any way and
you can't maybe talk to them about what
you're doing
and then there's the good friendships
which they may not like the same things
as you
um but today and if you needed any
deeper conversations they'd be there and
to be able to listen
and it's all about them so they're
giving off love for you rather than
being loved themselves sort of thing so
so yeah so came across that but yeah i
do do see a lot of
people who are lonely because once once
you've if you don't go to university
like most people go to university
they've got friends to
university and because i kind of got
moved about a bit
and all that at school so you never got
to bond with anyone there's proper
friendships and then
when you leave school you you don't have
the people that you're at school with
and then you're not in university
and may maybe you make friends at work
but that's highly unlikely because
nobody wants to see it after work
because it reminds you to work
um and then where do you go so like
after 25 to make friends well you turn
to the internet
and then obviously you meet people there
and some of them probably aren't all
that great
you know what i mean and if you try and
share anything with any depth at
all most of them kind of go get a grip
of yourself pull yourself together
whatever yeah you know i mean so it's
really difficult to try and
make friends and i've said if you move
to different cities
as well it's really difficult now to
actually
pub used to be a place you could
actually walk into and make friends with
people
and you'd have loads of pubs but
obviously you'd get drunk at the end of
the day get into a fucking mess as well
so um you can't do that you can't walk
into cafes now and just walk up to
someone and have a chat
without them thinking that you're mad
because because there's actually nowhere
to go
really um unless you've got a specific
interest and if you don't have any
interests
um that's odds as well so and obviously
as you get older and your husband dies
or whatever
then you're on your own and then you
find that the people
who you've been the both of you have
been friends with
um you don't they can't have a tendency
to keep away from you because they don't
know what to say
and they don't they don't want to make
you feel like they're inviting you to
things that are pity
you know i mean so as you get older you
realize as friends die
and that that you it's just really odd i
think making making proper good friends
with people that's um that's my
view on it we're like at the 15 minute
mark but i wanted to mention
um very real to this portion
is that even less about my loneliness
and personal needs because i'm
get i can figure out how to get my needs
met even though i also want in-person
community
my kid is reliant on
on me and i'm realizing there's two
people in the meeting
let me just admit mark and alex um that
there's
no that my kid needs to have friendships
and i have to be able to
help in some way like i feel like i'm
failing her with my social skills
like that she's she's coping well enough
because she's extremely extroverted and
can get her own needs met she met a
neighborhood friend and stuff but like
it's not
the same as your parent being good at
maintaining
friendships and relationships and having
those people in your life like aunts and
uncles and friends
and the other piece i want to mention
very much within linemen with autism
is the um the pity piece like i don't
want someone to be friends with me
because they pity me i want zero
of that i don't want to be included just
because you feel like you're supposed to
include me
oh i guess we'll let her talk about her
special interest and i guess you know
it's like if you don't like me for me
and want me to be there i don't want to
be there and it's really hard to find
that
it's hard to know when if people are
fake or not and welcome mark and alex
thanks for
for joining i'm sorry if you were in the
waiting room for a while and still
getting
getting used to that sorry i'm late you
guys have a quick few
um thoughts to share on your own
loneliness currently or in life
or in the world before we switch on to
the next section which is our ideal
future without lonely that's something
i'll let alex go first he got here
before i did
was the same oh maybe you guys are in
the morning
uh what was the question sorry um
just sharing loneliness that's what we
all the four of us shared what
loneliness means to us
and um yeah i think um
loneliness is is something that i'm sort
of very this is this is one area that
i've kind of i feel like i've wanted to
sort of focus on as
a problem i think you know by the way in
which our um
our system is structured and our
societies are uh
sort of formulated it doesn't actually
work really that well with our human
nature
um and especially just the kind of
layout of
you know especially cities and um and
things like that there's a there's a
real
there's a tendency for us moving towards
more loneliness especially now
so um yeah this is something that i've
kind of
um sort of thought a lot about in terms
of how you could
try and bring that back um through sort
of
you know generating trust between people
and and actually kind of
you know getting us back to the roots of
of of
who we are as uh as people so yeah i'm
glad to
i'm glad to be in on this one sorry i
came a bit
a bit late
well uh i just want to personally thank
everybody for being here because that's
helped with my loneliness right off the
bat
there's uh i think uh
for me it's it's
the lack of that authentic connection
and i can be lonely in a room full of
people i'm often alone in a room full of
people
but there
there is that deep authentic connection
that
i think i crave um
and it's it's kind of like
the hill i'm willing to die on and
it almost feels sometimes like
um because i've built that hill
that that feeling
of of loneliness is more extreme i don't
know if that's
the case or not or just something
imagined
but that's just my experience
yeah if you've tasted deep connection
then the absence of it is
even more painful right if you've never
known it then not having it is is far
less painful so yeah
yeah so um if we'd all been here at the
beginning i would have split us into two
groups and something tells me that we're
supposed to be all six of us that's why
we came in at the time we did so we will
continue with with this
um so now we switch over to the section
let's try to keep it a little briefer
since there are six of us
uh what you would like to see in your
ideal
future either globally like in the world
or in your own personal life what is it
what does a perfect
world look like in 5 10 20 years where
you maybe you don't have loneliness or
maybe it is part of who you are
our ideal futures don't need to match
whoever would like to start is welcome
well i'll jump in just because it
follows on from something that occurred
to me sort of in the opening section
that uh
listening to what everyone said there's
there seems to be a conflation
i'm not necessarily saying it's wrong
but a conflation between
uh lack of loneliness and friendship
right friendship with other people
and i don't think that's the whole
picture right i mean
like i said i have almost no contact
with people on a day-to-day basis right
i mean i have the occasional friend or
relative come and visit but you know i
live
day in day out go weeks sometimes
without seeing anyone or even speaking
to anyone on the phone or whatever
and so but the reason i don't get lonely
i think
is that because the connection thing
that mark is it
yeah mark yeah um the the the sense of
deep connection i think i think that's
the important thing and whether that's
with people or whether whether it's
whether it's with
a sense of purpose in your own life or
the or the
you know or the earth or whatever it
might be i i think
so long as you have that sense of being
connected
to something which is important right
then then
loneliness is held at bay and so i guess
in the in
in my perfect world everyone has found
their place and their purpose right
and and their like-minded people
naturally gravitate around them because
they have similar purposes right and
and and so yeah loneliness wouldn't
exist
but not as a consequence of better
social media or whatever and in making
it easier for people to find
friends sort of thing but just just
because people have a more
more whole and and complete in
themselves right because they
found something in this life which is
important to them which means something
something which they can
dedicate themselves to
uh i can go um
i think that in the ideal world i would
have
a way to know
who is available for
um for talking
or certain things very quickly
instead of having to text my friends and
acquaintances and say hey are you free
you know there would be a system where
they could actually
input their hey i'm free to talk i'm
free to talk all evening or hey i'm free
to
uh go play chess or whatever the thing
is
i my ideal world is there's like a
system
um where that could be communicated
uh by choice i i think that would be
super cool
yeah i'd say that's i'd agree with that
actually i think um i think it's it's
it's a little bit of a bit of both to me
in terms of
um being also uh partly
sort of slightly like having a better
social media but one that's not so
kind of intrusive and i guess it would
have to be
sort of intrusive i think that's where i
kind of see uh
this kind of potential is is making it
more efficient for people to find what's
what's meaningful for them
and then finding the people that that
they need to be able to go and do that
and then they
feel as though you know they have a more
import you know they have importance in
life they have
found people that are just as unique as
they
are but in very similar ways that
complement each other so i think
the only way we're going to be able to
actually kind of be able to do that
bring people together
around their kind of common values is is
by some kind of
understanding of of who we are whether
that's like
you know and somehow you know have that
go
through some kind of use of use of
technology to be able to
you know capture us in our real um
you know in our real being and then be
able to find those connections with the
people that
that we need so i think i'm i agree i
think it's one of these things where
it's
it feels like it needs to be fluid and
it needs to be like
easy you don't have to you know uh be
making like
effort to talk to this person this but
you know what i mean it needs to
it needs to feel more fluid i think our
technology has like separated us a bit
from our
um our kind of experience of of
connecting people i think if we can
bring back that synchronicity
in how we interact online that could
that could be a step i don't know
i love that i love that english
understatement i miss it separated us a
bit from our
yeah just a little bit
you gotta be honest i mean it's bringing
us together at the moment so you can't
you can't hate it too much well that's
how that's how it's been so successful
at separating this is it comes as a
trojan horse disguised as something
which is going to connect us
but actually it does the exact opposite
anyway sorry
there's other people want to talk
i i guess i can go um
i um it was interesting listening to
everybody and
because i i i wasn't gonna bring up
technology but i i can see how
um there there is there is
face for technology that that actually
works
and for me it would work in um
sustaining or facilitating that that
kind of deep connection that
authenticity that i was talking about so
if it could do that
if it could if it could provide
the space for that
really like authentic dialogue
and
facilitate the trust that you need and
and the kind of way of
i think uh alex mentioned it
just you're kind of the kind of real
authentic selves
making sure making sure um
allowing that to come through more
easily
so for me um the perfect world would
would be where that is the default the
authentic
vulnerable vulnerable self would be the
default
and i think that
from that a person could
much more easily discover their own
sense of meaning and connectedness
you know they it would be it would be
reflected in
the dialogues that you had it would be
it would be like a
felt thing and it would be
it would be um strengthened
and reflected anyways that's kind of
like
what i'm feeling okay
i think i'd agree with eric um on this
and i think daniel and alex need to be
chipped with the bat signal
[Laughter]
so beam a signal you know what
you need to be shifted to to put you
know project the bat signal
into the sky going yes i'm free
[Laughter]
no it's not said that it agree with eric
and and i think relationships anyway
and that loneliness and stuff i think
you know
with people it does take a bit of effort
you know i mean
and i think if you get the dart and then
you see that nobody's actually made an
effort
i think that makes you maybe feel more
lonely you know if there's something
there just click a button
and that's what you what it comes down
to you know so um
yeah but i think i think it even as long
as you found something that you need to
do i think people
you'll find the right people eventually
although it takes a long time
and sometimes you you know was it the
aristotle
thing said them between frogs and toads
or something
so you need to find toads
[Laughter]
frogs so
my ideal version of the future is a lot
of what you all talked about
um this deep authentic connection that
mark talked about
is and that it's the hell he's gonna die
on because yes when you've experienced
that
i like i'm not willing to do small talk
i'm not willing to do
the bullshit of like pretending we're
acquaintances and friends in order to
get to like the
realness and i don't know how much of
that is on me and how much is on other
people but having
a society where um
[Music]
i was surrounded by people but even if
they don't you know
no one's gonna accept you 100 for all of
your flaws there's going to be things
that great on your nerves that you don't
like
but take people as their full selves and
i know i can do that for other people so
having a community
both in person and online and just in
the greater world
that facilitates that facilitates you to
find people
who you have interest with like you know
facebook has all of our data
they they know who your best they know
who your best friends and mother and
stuff are but they also
theoretically know who could be your
best friend right like
who has everything in common with you
there's this other thing that's
happening
in my life right now with kobit 19 where
if i hang out with you in person three
to four times a year
you are one of my absolute best friends
whereas everyone else's metric that
makes you an acquaintance
and so as the phases have gone through
in realm and phase two and it's like all
right you're
you can connect with like best friends
you can connect with one other family
and i don't have that because i don't
have that like i'm like
your barry your metric is like we have
to hang out a couple times a week to be
best friends and mine is like a few
times a year
and so to be able to facilitate
the executive functioning piece of
hanging out so i don't have to do it
because that is a big sticking point
it's like but we have to decide when
we're both available and put it in
and then you know travel to where we're
going that's why one reason i like the
zoom meetings and stuff
is that it's just turn it on schedule it
people show up or they don't
and but to be able to offer because one
of the things i would love
as someone with a disability i sometimes
need help more and i'm less able to get
it
because i don't have i don't have that
connection of friendship to surround me
i did when i first had my brain tumors
and had surgery and then they slowly
fall away
as you don't show up to parties as you
don't show up to things they slowly fall
away
and so to be able and yet there are
disability networks and queer networks
and stuff that i know that i'm a part of
that i could put out a call for help and
they would help even though they've
never met me in my life
and having something like that that's an
emergency friendship button that is even
more needed by people who like
like it literally doesn't matter how
many times you need it
if you're in emergency you need to have
either emotional
financial something maybe the financials
a little tricky but like
contribution um and also that help
making long-lasting friends that aren't
going to be on a superficial level of
like
everyone likes fashion as a woman so
that's what we're going to talk about oh
fuck i don't want to talk about fashion
i don't care where you bought your shirt
i don't care if you like what i'm
wearing
like i just don't and so like i can't
get through the superficial to get to
the deep
i just want to talk about the deep like
let's talk about coven
or maybe not that one's overdone these
days but like let's talk about something
it's like actually real for you right
now and um i don't know if that talked
much about the ideal future but now we
can switch over so if anyone has any
closing thoughts they're welcome to do
it now let's do that first because
anyone have any closing thoughts if it's
in their ideal future before we move on
to adjacent possible
all right so the the third section i'm
gonna say final and i'm like we kind of
entered a fourth section of just the
very end we talked about what our most
powerful solution is
but what we could actually do to combat
loneliness with ten thousand people and
a hundred thousand dollars
so not a brand new facebook that
requires billions of people on it
like what would be something that ten
thousand people could do
and they each put in ten dollars so that
we have a hundred thousand dollars to
to create something
all right i've got i've i've got
something
this is this is this is basically how i
sort of imagine
we could do this because this is this is
something i've kind of
you know thought about how you could say
combat sort of facebook if
this is very kind of this this might be
kind of based around
you know using a technological aspect at
first um
but i but to me it looks that you know
one of the main reasons that
facebook is able to to to make all these
um
understandings of us is by the fact that
we give it so much of our data that of
course then
you know to be able to be useful it has
to then sell it to somewhere else
who can then you know pair it with other
stuff to be able to bring it into
something that makes
this useful so that we can be be sold
better stuff so it's so it's like really
we need to be able to reverse that
um we need to be able to actually like
own our own data
and have sovereignty over ourselves
online and how we act online and what it
what
what that what that algorithm knows
about us effectively
um for us to be able to actually you
know do anything that's that's different
you know to be able to flip that that
model um because i think
um you know
they're not going to give it up very
easily that's the thing it's just like
that's what that's why this time is
quite interesting is because it's kind
of like the
the oil uh companies of the past
when once you know they have no
incentive to
to to move over to something that they
haven't already been
completely um you know created by
so in in that sense you know there's
going to be this this change
because if we do want if we if we agree
that those kind of
um that power that facebook has to be
able to manipulate democracy or
you know uh um completely kind of change
our mindsets on stuff
unless we're able to take that back and
have have agency in how we use it
then um you know i think i think we're
always going to get into this
um into this issue we're never really
going to be able to use it
properly for ourselves so to to me i
think you know especially if you had
10 000 people um all of those 10 000
people
being able to create their own place
online where
all of their data is is centralized and
it just tracks them everywhere they go
and they never have to click accept ever
again and
they can just have this thing that knows
them so well
but as long as it's you know i think
this is this is where it kind of comes
into
the idea of security like if if we are
going to be our authentic selves and be
vulnerable
and have something that is very kind of
feels very intrusive
it needs to have that sense of security
and
and to me that's almost like the the
sort of
i think we all kind of need that need
some sense of security to feel
vulnerable so that we can
you know actually connect with one
another so that we can you know have
have community alex what is is your
background in tech
no yeah because i i feel and i'm my
background's not in tech either but it's
like my passion what i'm trying to put
in the world
i feel like a repository for your data i
would love that and i don't think it's
feasible for a hundred thousand dollars
like i think
all right i mean like how would i get my
data from facebook and google when
they're not even willing to give it if
we had millions of dollars let alone for
you know
like we what could we create with ten
thousand people and a hundred thousand
dollars that we could use
right without needing to to get
permission from google or facebook
because i love that idea i want access
to my own data
but i don't to me i because i was like
if you know how to do that for a hundred
thousand dollars let's get on that let's
call that right now
yeah certainly totally i could you could
you can download like they
they've now sort of made it so that you
you can download your own data
um so like you can actually you know
take take all of that and
and have it there the one thing i don't
know is whether you can
make it readable so you can if it if you
can
you know facebook allows you to download
all of your all of your facebook data
and so does google
so really if you started downloading all
of these things from somewhere else
and then we're able to to make them talk
to each other and be able to
create a kind of map and then that map
can also be kind of the thing is you you
need to be able to have
a way for it to be um the kind of
insights to be able to generate it
but you you need it so that you're not
sending it to a bunch of places it's
more that it has you know like an
access point um so i don't like yeah i
don't know if you could do that in
with with uh how much is it hundred
thousand
hundred thousand dollars a month
and i could tell you if you guys can
give me a hundred thousand dollars okay
okay
everyone always wanted like if i had
that money um
one of the things i think you could
actually easily do with ten thousand
people
and so we can do a hundred thousand
dollars is
create a culture of deep
authentic connection so what that now
that doesn't just mean that it is that
and i find a lot of
what happens online right now is very
social justice pc culture of like here's
our umbrella terms of service
if you fail in any way you're cancelled
and it doesn't make help people feel
safe it doesn't give us deep authentic
connection yet we don't want to get rid
of all of that and have you know like
neo-nazis and and home folks come in
you know like sling that around at the
same time having that fear
cancel culture and not being able to
show up as your authentic self and
having to worry about
wait do i look okay on camera do i this
do i that that having a space where
you're allowed to make mistakes where
there is a road to redemption
where we agree being on whatever this
platform is that we are going to show up
as ourselves as much as we can
and accept other people and when we come
into conflict
um we'll deal with it meaning that like
you know if i'm sitting with someone who
i
absolutely can't stand instead of
requiring everyone cancel them
i can block them right i never have to
sit with them again
but i don't need everyone else to cancel
this human being because the best thing
for them is to be connected and happy
and healthy that they're like they're
going to be the best
version of their worst human self like
even if i think they're a bad human
being they're going to be their best
version of a bad human being in that
connection
and safety and so i think that a culture
of inclusivity
is something it's just how would you do
that without it being like
um especially for the first ten thousand
you you don't want it to be like
trolls compensate a safe troll space for
you
but i think ten thousand people putting
in ten dollars for that deep authentic
connection
wouldn't be trolls and therefore would
be show especially since they're putting
money in right they're like
not gonna put ten dollars in to come and
troll in six months when it's created
but maybe we'll see
yeah you know um although
i was earlier i was talking about oh
yeah i'd love a system where people
could
basically say if they're available to
chat or not because like you know the
way i do it is i've got my you know
i've got my uh 12 or 13
friends that if i'm need a conversation
and especially you know
loneliness uh it gets weird in the
evening when people
are not as available um and so i you
know go down my list who can i call
after 9 45 who can i call at like 10 30
at night if that's
you know and there's part of loneliness
is like befriending your loneliness and
not avoiding it
and like that's a part of this and
uh that you know like that's a whole
nother conversation but
um yeah so i'll go down the list of
people i can call
later at night and like you know wait
till i get one
you know someone who can answer who's
who's free and so
the system would let people say if they
are already available without me having
to call them
and wonder you know and like get five
missed calls before i hit someone who's
free
um that's all i was talking about with
that um
but on as far as like creating the
culture
um that's you know i don't have a good
solution for this but my solution would
be a little bit more um of teaching
um and a little bit more like hey we're
practicing what we're gonna do
and we're inviting people into that one
at a time and
and teaching them um i've had some
i'm lucky to have some experience with
that eric hit the nail on the head when
he said
when you have experienced those very
very
deep connection great authentic
relationships
then when many of your other
relationships can seem so lacking they
can seem
so shallow when you know how good it can
be
and that's what i see in the world is
people don't even know what they're
missing out of
on because they've never had anyone say
oh you can tell me what your sorrows are
and i will you know be with you and
receive i don't have a solution but i'll
be with you in that
in the recovery community we do a lot of
stuff like that
um there's a there's a knowing there's
like oh you too
you know i've been there too and that
helps connect people
um but i i would go for um 10
000 people gosh i would go for slightly
more of like a teaching model
i didn't make some of this stuff up
there's another author i really like
that talks about
joys and sorrows and he says if you want
to experience
a lot of joy with others you
also have to experience sorrows with
them
it doesn't mean reliving them but i need
you to know my whole truth
or i can't laugh with you until you know
i carry this burden of abuse or i carry
this burden of
fatherlessness whatever it is it's i'm
gonna have a hard time
being relaxed and i'm gonna have a hard
time
laughing with you and so he says up sets
up this joys and sorrows model and he's
like the deeper you can go in your
sorrows with another human being
is the deeper you can is the higher you
can go with the joys
um it's an authenticity thing again
isn't it i mean if you if you're
it's if you're withholding parts of
yours if they don't know this about you
and it informs you know how you think
and who you are and how you behave and
so on and they don't know that about you
then
that and you're there is always this
whether you're fully conscious of it or
not there's always this screen up
between you right because there's this
thing about me you don't know and i
could that
it sort of like blocks the flow right it
is an authenticity because you're not
there with your
with your whole self and you kind of
said that i'm just trying to link it
back to the notion of authenticity
so that's that's appears like a big
um salve for loneliness is being able to
teach this and and teach by showing
people this is how it works
this is in in some communities i've been
in that are good like this
we basically say i'm gonna show you how
deep i can go i can show you how
vulnerable i can get
in this wound i've experienced and all
of a sudden someone feels safe and
they're like
oh i didn't know we could talk about
that like
um and that's
hey if 10 000 people built a network
of doing that and it fanned out i don't
even know what the money has to do with
it but
hey that's all i got that would be huge
i mean having a space where you know you
could be vulnerable
even if you weren't going to make those
deep connections lifelong to just know
like akira's emotional dojo
which is more about anger and conflict
in relationship than like
share your most vulnerable story but
there is
a piece to that what came from when you
were first talking
was i had this idea for almost like
instead of business cards which are out
of
sight they're not really current anyway
right people have more electronic ones
having more of a personal
business slash disability card like tell
me who you are
right what do you need to thrive what do
you need in the in like how do i know
there's so many assumptions i make on
people that we all have to make
like that i shouldn't call anyone past
10 p.m at night or call anyone before
you know
8 a.m in the morning that's not true
there's some people who don't want to be
called during that time and would be
fine to do with a 2 am phone call
knowing what time of day you're okay
with
knowing that you need a quiet place to
meet if we're going to meet in public
no like knowing what like maybe i need
to know what you've taken your coffee
and so i put out a request all of my
you know all of the friends because i'm
like that
it can be crowdsourced both what we want
to know
and what we want to offer right so
you're not if i don't want to share my
coffee
requirements i don't have to that feels
a little vulnerable right that like
i get to choose but having something
like that that is
in addition to real life and online what
do you need
like i would love to be able to explain
to everyone my disability without having
to explain my disability all the time to
be like listen i'm not gonna write you
back i'm
you know it's not i don't like you as a
human being the things i do are gonna
make you feel like i don't like you as a
human being
i absolutely do i just can't do
like i can't meet that level i have a
i have a good friend with asd and and we
talk about that a lot
and he's like i don't want to announce
to every new people that i meet that i
have asd like that's not
fun for me
at the same time like
if new folks don't know
then they may be confused
sometimes and they have to sort of
figure it out and they spend the first
five minutes and they can't tell and
then
10 minutes into an interaction they
notice
something strange is going on and then
but if you could just say
he had asd right when he met them then
they
would have a better expectations of the
interaction
but that's not fun for him how can you
know what are you supposed to do
like so
yeah i guess when you start getting the
puzzle looked and the and the
and the exchange first of glances like
what is what's up with this guy then
there's the moment
by the way if i seem to be acting a bit
oddly it's because i have this condition
you know
yeah and he can't pick up on when things
are getting strange and
it's a whole it's a whole thing but hey
you know everybody's got something that
goes back to the whole thing of
that i mean vulnerability is risky but i
think
it's it's needed for better friendships
and vet and better
connections if i have this facade
up you don't really know the whole me um
i mean there's reasonable boundaries you
know you don't jump in
all the way right away uh because
some people will hurt you back but
um yeah if they're
the solution thing if there was a
network of you know where
trusted people because i do think trust
is a little bit transferable
um and you know if you
if i build a huge amount of trust with
you i can introduce you to my friend
over here
that you don't know as well but i say
hey i've known this person eight years
we're really close you can transfer some
of the trust
um that stuff is helpful
yeah i totally i totally agree i think
that's that's you know
by the fact that so much of everything
we do in life is is that anyway
in the way in which you know a lot of
the time you'll you'll meet cool friends
and then your friends will introduce you
to other cool friends it's one of these
things where you'll
you'll know you know and even in work
everyone will be
you know a lot of times so many um jobs
are filled by
by recommendations because you know good
people will who are who are high and
who have a sort of um belief to get to a
certain point or whatever will also be
hanging around other people or working
in similar situations so
when we we we do that anyway and i think
you know by the fact that
people can sort of disappear from each
other and and have a sort of
um have a kind of complete break that
um that means that we almost are needing
that
solution of being able to vouch for
somebody else and go okay i'm
you know i've developed a certain trust
with that person
um and i think if you had a network of
you know
10 000 people all just being able to
you know really show how much trust they
had in
in somebody else um that would really
allow like so much more kind of fluid
kind of collaboration to work work
between them and
um and it kind of kind of makes me feel
like having um you almost want like a
like a manual
of yourself that you know if we were
gonna do it super slow
you you'd sort of get to get to know
somebody before you almost meet them
um i don't know how you would kind of
present that but
i think you know that's almost a way to
kind of get around
that that whole kind of on-boarding
people into your into your
uh personality so so what if you had
i mean i i feel like on the topic of
loneliness
there's these different types like i
talked about
like i could have a group of people that
i had great
conversations with this knowing
authenticity
piece but i still felt lonely because i
really want to go rock climbing with
someone and i just haven't found that
person and
or i have all these rock climbing
friends but everybody's really shallow
i think like the thing we could probably
more practically concentrate on
is having some kind of i i love the idea
of
like jubilee mentioned what if i did let
people know yeah
you can actually call me till like one
in the morning i'm that type of person
like i'll probably pick up and
i'll probably be there for you but
people just don't know that they see
they see dan and they're like oh well
he's a working professional i probably
can't call him after nine like because
that's
whatever but that'd be cool to have
something
like that it just
i think one of the things we've touched
on but not quite is like with loneliness
a lot of what can combat it is activity
right whether that activity is a
conversation
because that's where i get my deep
authentic connection from is by sharing
and finding learning about people and
seeing them but also the rock climbing
or the you know recovery or any of those
things they're around an activity
so an event and having something like
meetup
but for online and offline events where
you are
curating your life right you're saying
hey i'm really good
actually but i also really want to
partner rock climb with and can just put
that out into the universe and based on
your circle of people
and you know like here's someone in your
in your area daniel
who rock climbs would you like to be
connected like the activity
thing is covered by some
things like meetup but
you know i'm not sure that the
uh
i don't know the uh understanding
availability
of friends i already have just to talk
is covered
anywhere i still guess my this is like
with meetup itself meetup is great i
don't want to just
but like we don't own meetup and we
can't improve it so we can't
you know like we can i don't want to
find
all of the club things that i'm i would
maybe be interested in and then when are
they having activities i have to go in
and see if they have an activity and am
i available and am i not available
that's way too much work i want to say
i'm jubilee
here's what i'm available here are the
activities i enjoy and something can
give like be like oh you should connect
with this person or there's a baseball
game
there's a fire there's a singing out in
nature activity that you want to be part
of
here you go that like the more really
the more unique it is the more
that that would be useful to curate your
dashboard of activity right to say okay
and if there's any obstacles
that we can be like well i'd love to do
that but i don't have a ride
oh we need 2.0 to have a ride share
version right that like because we own
it and the point isn't to make money for
meetup the point is connection
and so we're going to want each in
iteration to be um
better and meet our connection
loneliness needs more so than make money
for us right and that is part of the
technology cooperative
vision is that everything we create
together is for purpose not for profit
so if we're creating something to combat
loneliness
we're doing it for ourselves the 10 000
people and then
continually improving it it's like what
is 1.0 what does beta look like
the first version and then how do we
continually improve it because
meetup exists but we don't own it and we
can't improve it and that's the big
thing are we still going around doing
that what we would do for ten thousand
dollars
yeah absolutely mark i'd love to hear
your ideas i'm just like i'd like to
hear someone else
first i know there's two other people
that haven't gone
i'd like to hear them first i think it's
just you and kerry old chat
i think everyone else has had to say
it's just you and kerry
kerry's microphone is clearly broken
again no
i think she stopped me no don't just
mute myself
i know just kidding he's like a
sarcastic font
i don't think i've got a lot of road
noise
maybe i should have muted are you guys
hearing a lot of road noise or anything
like that
um no okay it's a little quiet but nope
it's fine
i i um i i liked a lot of what i was
hearing
the the part i
i i was really impressed by holotape
um and in that it it can carry a lot of
that information
um it it can sense all the nodes around
it
that are close to it and it it can
um it carries like a it's like it's
like blockchain on steroids because it
it
it can carry that ledger information off
everything you interacted with
up to that point or everything this
thing interacted with so
the idea of being able to
to know to have everything about you
in there and um
i guess it would be like offering how
would you say that
bids of information this is possibly
what i want
everyone to know within a certain trust
circle and your trust
could be distributed i'm seeing
and so people will know
all of that also if you could
probably build in with an algorithm an
ability to
uh to know those things that are on the
periphery of my knowledge
or my interest or things i might be
interested in
and then have it present opportunities
to you
from the other interactive nodes or
nodes that just joined in
in that group of 10 000 where the
opportunities are
so i think that's possible with 10 000
people and
and and i think the fruits of that would
be
that you would enable creative people to
come up with things that
would blow others away and people
say where the fuck are these people
coming from you know what's
really where they get these ideas how
are they able to
to do these things and then they
they point to that that that community
and i think that the fruit of that would
drive people to want to get in
and you know there's only one way in you
got to be vulnerable
you got to be totally vulnerable and you
got to be trusted
so that's your way in
definitely down to last few minutes as
the part where we can go around and then
we never stop there um
and say what they you think is the most
powerful part of what you could do with
ten thousand
people and a hundred thousand dollars
and carrie you're more than welcome to
start and or and then share you nah
i'm not gonna say no sorry you don't you
don't wanna
okay um
the most powerful one for me is one that
includes it all
one that includes like how but the
information that i can give you so that
i can show up and be vulnerable without
needing to constantly add all these tag
lines about like
my disability and my past and all of
this stuff would be very powerful for me
personally but also
within that a emergency button like
something that is like i need help
now and you just push it and something
goes out either your circle or random
strangers that like
in crisis because it's the time when
you're least able to do that for
yourself and when you most need it
yeah i think um i was just i just wanted
to echo what um
what mark was saying because i think i'm
very aligned to to
to what that looks like um and i feel
it's exactly that way of of us kind of
forming
sort of new um new tribes and new kind
of partnerships with other people
on larger scales that will allow us to
have some of that creativity and
innovation
that will be the kind of great attractor
that you know
um like daniel schweinsteiger always
talk about it's like
something like that would would would
generate that by the fact that
everyone is um you know able to really
leverage each other and actually
by going into partnership in the long
term with people and and being
vulnerable and improving
yourself and and in in relationship with
other people
um i think the the fruits of that could
be um
could be super exponential you know it
could be one of those things where if
you have that kind of community and it's
and it goes by
by like slowly um passing the trust
forward into a network um i think all
you really need is that like commitment
of those those
ten thousand or even less than that just
uh um
just to put it into into play so
yeah that's and um
yeah and i just wanna also say that in
terms of the um
i noticed this a lot in the pandemic as
well it's just by the fact that what you
were saying jubilee where you just need
you know a need to be able to just be
like sent out there and then
it finds the right right people um i
felt like that was just
so clear that everyone all of a sudden
everyone's needs and
and and haves were all scattered around
and
and if if there was a way of being like
oh shit i've run out of toilet you know
this old lady is running out of toilet
roll let me just run down and
and give us some of mine then you know
half of our almost all of our that's a
small
example but that was in telehealth that
was exactly that was exactly what
intellihelp was
and i don't know if they're still going
or how big it got or whatever i actually
stopped paying attention to it a few
months ago
but that's it but that's exactly what
that was yeah was that the one where
they
um somebody would say i have this you
know and and somebody else would
exactly right a series of boards and you
know you would you would search your
area for
you know people who had spare capacity
people who need
unmet for whatever reason and yeah i
mean
certainly in its early stages it was
working really well and lots of people
were using it and it was actually
you know and people were writing their
thank you notes and all that and it was
it was really going great guns i've no
idea what it became
subsequently i think i mean we've only
been in the pandemic for
how many months it takes while yeah it
feels like a lot more of that
already virus works faster than coding
what do you think is the most powerful
thing we talked about today eric or the
most
powerful thing to combat loneliness um
i mean they've kind of all been
variations on a theme haven't they you
know
ways to connect people who are likely to
be
good candidates for friendship with each
other right and that's that's that's the
thing i mean i
i again i i i my personal belief is i
guess none of you really agree with it
because none of you picked up on it and
fair enough
um but i i i think
connections to other people are
important yes but it's only part of it
you can have
good friendships in your life and still
feel lonely because
you know you're feeling purposeless or
direction
purposeless or directionless or whatever
it might be and you know you can talk to
your friends about it it doesn't
actually alleviate the things so i i do
think i don't know the the
the a lack of connection to something
deep in yourself
is something that cannot be assuaged
with
all the relationships in the world right
there you must also have that
so yeah i don't know what i don't know
how that fits into the ten thousand
people hundred thousand dollars i think
it doesn't really but i i
it just seems to be a missing part of
the conversation in general
all right i don't know who is shared
they're powerful i know alex did i did i
daniel did i'll share mark kind of did
because mark was at the end and then to
be
completed but i don't know uh i
thoroughly enjoyed this whole
conversation
i think i picked up on like three or
four different
um semi-related ideas it's just
all all good i really like the jubilee
i guess i could echo what you said as a
practical thing
as some kind of business card
maybe digital business card but not a
business card
uh i think that's i think that's super
cool um
so i i think it's just important to
remember i think about the
there's the five love languages thing
and so we have a big danger of
projecting
like i have the answer because i know
what connects me to people but
people are connected by different styles
um and so we've got to remember it's
different styles for different
people i connect by talking someone else
connects
by uh doing you know there's
these best differences and on the
vulnerability thing so i
i agree with that i was just gonna share
that um
i learned that you know i'm from the usa
i learned that my father's generation
was basically told vulnerability is
weakness
vulnerability is the enemy and never
show your weakness because that doesn't
make a man
and that doesn't and like i i'm um
very hopeful for our generation because
i keep getting in conversations where
people
seem to realize that's actually not
the way um and that's makes me hopeful
anyone else like to share their most
powerful idea before we stop recording
and i'm watching tomorrow
i guess i'd like to just um
let eric know that he's not he's not
alone with um
feeling that meaning and revealing that
meaning in yourself
is is is important
um i i just think that um
authentic dialogue and being present and
sometimes just witnessing you know not
saying anything you could be a
one of a hundred witnesses but just
witnessing with somebody
can allow you to get some of that
meaning and even give some of that
meaning
so i think that's that's important but i
think
a lot of these ideas about scaling trust
how to scale that's critical we got to
figure that out
if we can because if if we can't
we're looking here
just just one thing on this notion of
skating i mean i really like the idea of
the transferability of trust i think
that's a really cool idea
however this is weaponizable right
because trust now becomes a commodity on
this network right it's a valuable
commodity and people will start
selling their trust to people oh you
give me a thousand quid and i'll say
that i trust you a hundred percent and
then all the people that know me and
trust me
they see my trust to this person which
isn't actually real trust it's been
bought
you know what i mean and and so the the
network can easily become corrupted in
this manner
it's true and there's other ways it can
be corrupted i just want to invite
carrie do you want to share before we
we stop recording okay i just thank you
all for
joining we're having a one-off one
tomorrow on voting
with your wallet it starts at this time
so it starts at 10 a.m
tomorrow mark and i are doing it and
everyone's invited and we will be
breaking off into groups of three to
five
that's why we didn't break off today
what's this voting with your wallet
thing what's this
it's just another solution raising but
it's and i did want to just
well you guys were talking we were
having this like we're talking about
loneliness and deep connection and
vulnerability
and we are not 10 000 people we are six
people
but i feel like this is actually a
solution to loneliness and connection
and i wanted to acknowledge what alex
and mark shared the beginning of the
most powerful section
i do think is the most powerful part to
create game b
it's not wasn't necessarily the most
powerful for loneliness but yeah
creating
a solution for loneliness that's a
natural attractor
is how we create game b so i'm just
gonna stop the recording now